Cobb Family Papers
Cobb Family Papers
- Writings
  - Cobb, Stanwood
    - Articles,preliminary plays, outlines
      - "Man's Illuminatable Progress", 1936 (Box 22)
      - "Mardi-Gras for Turks", 1908 (Box 22)
      - "The Meaning of Evil", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Men, Don't Be Ashamed to Weep", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "The Miracle of Shakespeare", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "The New Education Fellowship", 1920 (Box 22)
      - "A New Movement in Education", 1921 (Box 22)
      - "The New Patriotism", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Newspapers", 1905 (Box 22)
      - "Our Faults", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Our Friends Over There", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "The Philosophic Background of China" (Box 22)
      - "Learning to Teach" (Box 22)
      - "The Place of Bret Harte in American Literature", 1902 (Box 23)
      - "Poor Billionaires" (Box 23)
      - "Preparing for an Education", 1923 (Box 23)
      - "Progressive Education" (Box 23)
      - "On Progressive Education", 1932 (Box 23)
      - "The Progressive Education Association", 1919-1921 (Box 23)
      - "Progressive Education as it is Today", 1931 (Box 23)
      - "Quality Education" (Box 23)
      - "Religion and Science" (Box 23)
      - "Religiosity versus Spirituality, unpublished (Box 23)
      - "The Sayings of Brother Aloysius", unpublished (Box 23)
      - "Science to Serve Man" (Box 23)
      - "Science Thinking", unpublished (Box 23)
      - "The Simple Life in the Orient", 1912 (Box 23)
      - "Some Thoughts on Culture" (Box 23)
      - "The Spirit of Joy", unpublished (Box 23)
      - "The Spirituality of East and West" (Box 23)
      - "The Story of the Progressive Schools" (Box 23)
      - "Superficial Americans" (Box 23)
      - "Teaching Composition" (Box 23)
      - "Theirs is the Kingdom of Heaven", unpublished (Box 23)
      - "Those Center-Stage Children", unpublished (Box 23)
      - "Those Remarkable Twins" (Box 23)
      - "Tramps About Constantinople", 1910; includes photographs; unpublished (Box 23)
      - "Traveling for an Education", 1913 (Box 23)
      - "Travel Schools for the American Boy", 1912; unpublished (Box 23)
      - "A Tribute to Sara Farmer" (Box 23)
      - On Turkey and Europe, 1907-1912 (Box 23)
      - On Turkey, untitled, 1910 (Box 23)
      - "The Unexplored Regions of the Mind", unpublished (Box 24)
      - "The Unspeakable Turk", 1908 (Box 24)
      - "A Vicarious Sacrifice", unpublished (Box 24)
      - "The Way of America", 1944 (Box 24)
      - "The Way to Progress and Happiness", 1933 (Box 24)
      - "Well Living at Vassar" (Box 24)
      - "What is Bahai?" (Box 24)
      - "What is the Matter with Our Schools?", unpublished (Box 24)
      - "What is Progressive Education" (Box 24)
      - "What Makes a Person Creative?", unpublished (Box 24)
      - "What Our Middies Read", 1917; clipping (Box 24)
      - "What Should We Do Without CO2?" (Box 24)
      - "What the World Wants" (Box 24)
      - "Why Do Children Balk at Study?" (Box 24)
      - "Women and Genius" (Box 24)
    - Book reviews, Boston Evening Transcript, 1905-1907; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Books
      - Novel on education and religion, notes, research material (Box 24)
      - Novel outlines (Box 24)
      - Similia
        - Drafts, 1917; 2 folders (Box 24)
        - Draft, 1919 (Box 25)
        - Reviews, 1919 (Box 25)
      - Book(s) on science, notes, research material (Box 25)
      - Fragments (Box 25)
      - Preliminary plan, unfinished (Box 25)
      - The Achievement of Living, outline (Box 25)
      - America's Quest, unpublished (Box 25)
      - Creative Man, 1934; notes, research material (Box 25)
      - Creative Man, reviews (Box 25)
      - Spiritual Psychology, outline and preface (Box 25)
      - Spiritual Psychology for Human Development, 1935 (Box 25)
      - Character: A Sequence in Spiritual Psychology, 1938 (Box 25)
      - Character: A Sequence in Spiritual Psychology, 1939; reviews (Box 26)
      - Contributions of Islamic Science to World Civilization, 1963 (Box 26)
      - "The Cultural Awakening of America" (Box 26)
      - Discovering the Genius Within You (Box 26)
        - Reviews (Box 26)
        - Research material (Box 26)
        - Summary (Box 26)
        - Clippings, 1925-1936; 3 folders (Box 26)
        - Introduction (Box 26)
        - Preliminary outline (Box 26)
        - Chapter XII (Box 26)
        - pp. 1-125, 1931 (Box 27)
      - The Donkey or the Elephant, 1951 (Box 27)
      - On education, notes, research material (Box 27)
      - On education, preliminary plans, research material (Box 28)
      - On education, unpublished draft (Box 28)
      - The Essential Mysticism, 1918 (Box 28)
      - The Essential Mysticism, 1919; reviews (Box 28)
      - Harmony, preliminary plans (Box 28)
      - "A History of Progressive Education in the U.S.", appendix (Box 28)
      - On homoculture, preliminary plan for book (Box 29)
      - On Islam, notes, research material (Box 29)
      - Islamic Contributions to Civilization, 1962; drafts; 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Islamic Contributions to Civilization, 1963 (Box 29)
      - The Loves of Shelly, unpublished; 5 folders (Box 30)
      - The Loves of Shelly, unpublished; 1 folder (Box 31)
      - The Magnificent Partnership, 1954 (Box 31)
      - Man in the Universe
        - Drafts, 3 folders (Box 31)
        - Research (Box 31)
        - Unused fragments, 1962-1963 (Box 31)
        - Preface, 1962-1963 (Box 32)
        - Introduction (Box 32)
        - Chapters, topics include Schweitzer, Tolstoy, Jewish mysticism, intuition, spiritual healing, etc.; 23 folders (Box 32)
        - Drafts (Box 32)
        - Drafts, 4 folders (Box 33)
      - Man's Search for God, 1954 (Box 33)
      - On mass culture (Box 33)
      - The Meaning of Life, 1932 (Box 33)
      - New Horizons for the Child, 1934 (Box 33)
      - New Horizons for the Child, 1934; reviews (Box 33)
      - New Leaven, appendices; unpublished (Box 33)
      - On mass culture, 1940 (Box 33)
      - New Leaven, 1928 (Box 34)
      - "The Power of Prayer", unpublished (Box 34)
      - The Real Turk, 1914 (Box 34)
      - The Sage of the Sacred Mountain, 1953 (Box 34)
      - Security in a Failing World, 1934 (Box 34)
      - Security in a Failing World, 1935; reviews (Box 35)
      - Symbols of America, 1946 (Box 35)
      - Symbols of America, 1947; reviews, publisher's description (Box 35)
      - Tomorrow and Tomorrow, 1952 (Box 35)
      - "Use Your Mind", preliminary plan (Box 35)
      - "What is Wrong with our Schools?", 1921 (Box 35)
      - The Jade Necklace of Lin San Kwei, 1958 (Box 35)
      - What is Love?, 1957; early draft (Box 35)
      - What is God?, 1955 (Box 35)
      - What is Man?, 1952 (Box 35)
      - Wu Ming Fu series
        - Drafts, notes, 1942 (Box 36)
        - Quotations (Box 36)
        - Patters in Jade of Wu Ming Fu, 1934; drafts (Box 36)
        - The Way of Life of Wu Ming Fu, 1942 (Box 36)
        - The Wisdom of Wu Ming Fu, 1931 (Box 36)
        - The Wisdom of Wu Ming Fu, 1935; reviews (Box 36)
    - Diaries, 1893-1897; 6 volumes (Box 36)
    - Diaries, 1898-1910; 12 volumes (Box 37)
    - Diaries, 1911 (Box 38)
    - Notebooks, 1898-1899; 1905; prose and verse; 2 volumes (Box 38)
    - Plays
      - Miscellaneous, plot outlines (Box 38)
      - Hospital Scene (Box 38)
      - The Runaway, plot outline (Box 38)
      - Untitled, written for children at Chevy Chase school to perform, unpublished (Box 38)
      - Untitled, 1905-1907 (Box 38)
    - Research papers
      - "Aesthetics", 1903; outline (Box 38)
      - "The Development of Poetic Style", 1904 (Box 38)
      - "History of Communism", 1907 (Box 38)
      - "Marcus Aurelius", 1906; Harvard (Box 38)
      - "Modern Types of Mysticism", 1907 (Box 38)
    - Essays
      - "Nietzsche", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The World Order of Marcus Aurelius", 1906 (Box 38)
    - Sermons
      - Miscellaneous notes (Box 38)
      - "Cease from anger and forsake wrath", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The end of desire", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The God we worship", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The joy of religion", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The liberty of the Sons of God", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The motives for conduct", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "Religion", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "The religion of feelings and the religion of action", 1906 (Box 38)
      - "Should a minister be first of all a citizen?", 1906 (Box 38)
      - Untitled (Box 39)
    - Short stories
      - "Arillo's Ring", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - "The Burning of Old Dartmouth Hall", 1904 (Box 39)
      - "The Charm of Bad Gastein", unpublished (Box 39)
      - "A Country Wedding", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - "The Death of a Nurse" (Box 39)
      - "Fame and Immortality", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - "The Fortunes of Haroun" (Box 39)
      - "Judartha", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - "The Project of Mr. Ashley", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - "The Valley of Children", unpublished (Box 39)
      - "Virful Cu Dor", 1904-1907 (Box 39)
      - Untitled, 1904-1907 (Box 39)
    - Speeches and lectures
      - "Beginning of Life", 1935 (Box 39)
      - On college, 1930 (Box 39)
      - "The coming world civilization" (Box 39)
      - On education, 1929; at Penn State (Box 39)
      - On genius (Box 39)
      - On Islam, 1936 (Box 39)
      - "Learning to think", 1938 (Box 39)
      - "Man's spiritual life" (Box 39)
      - "The philosophy of leadership" (Box 39)
      - "The place of sound in poetry and literature" (Box 39)
      - On primitive religion (Box 39)
      - On progressive education (Box 39)
      - "The Green Acre Story" (Box 39)
      - Salutatory address, Newton High (Box 39)
      - On schools (Box 39)
      - "Where is America's bourgeois culture leading to?" (Box 39)
      - "Universal free education" (Box 39)
    - Verse
      - Miscellaneous, early (Box 39)
      - Miscellaneous, 1907-1915 (Box 39)
      - "The decision of faith" (Box 39)
      - "To Mabel" (Box 39)
      - "Newton: a poetic appreciation" (Box 39)
      - "Pilgrimage of the soul", drafts; 2 folders (Box 40)
      - "Reassurance" (Box 40)
      - "Sunset", 1899 (Box 40)
      - "The word" (Box 40)
      - See also oversize #1
  - Cobb, Sylvanus
    - Articles (Box 40)
    - Book, Compend of Divinity, 1846 (Box 40)
    - Diaries, 1825-1839; 3 volumes (Box 40)
    - Poem, "For Laura Dear", marriage proposal in verse (Box 40)
    - Speeches, 1862 (Box 40)
  - Cobb family, miscellaneous
    - Poem, Cyrus C., "American Union" (Box 40)
    - Poem, Cyrus C., "Banner of Light", 1847 (Box 40)
    - Poem, Cyrus C., "Banner of Light", 1850 (Box 40)
    - Articles published in The Christian Freeman and Family Visiter [sic]
      - Miscellaneous fragments, 1862 (Box 40)
      - Untitled, Sylvanus C. and Cyrus C., 4 Nov 1859 (Box 40)
      - Untitled, Sylvanus C. and Darius C., 11 Nov 1859; includes poem (Box 40)
      - Untitled, Sylvanus C. and Cyrus C., 26 Nov 1859 (Box 40)
      - Untitled, Cyrus C., 18 May 1860 (Box 41)
      - Untitled, Sylvanus C. and Cyrus C., 25 May 1860 (Box 41)
      - "East Boston Ledger", 7 Nov 1861 (Box 41)
      - "Flag of our Union," Cyrus C., 1862 (Box 41)
      - "National Merchant," Darius C., 1861 (Box 41)
      - "The New York Ledger", 1861 (Box 41)
      - "Trumpet and Christian Freemen", fragments (Box 41)
      - "The Union League and National Educator," Cyrus C., 1855 (Box 41)
      - "The Wide World," Darius C., Aug 1862 (Box 41)
    - Poem, Mildred Cram, "The Perfect Gift for Understanding" (Box 41)
    - Lecture, Mary Baker Eddy (Box 41)
    - Poem, Mary Lofgren, inspired by Darius Cobb painting; poem, Robert Sanborn, "A Warning from the Heart", 1915 (Box 41)
    - Book, Elihu Vedder, Doubt and Other Things, 1922 (Box 41)